Guide to the Typographical collection, 1812-1956
Department of Special Collections
Typographical collection,
1812-1956
Special Collections M0137
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Various sources.
Scope and Content
Single items and small collections (letters and some printed matter) by or about printers, publishers, book-binders, book dealers, bibliophiles and etc. 1812 - 1956.
Container List
- ARLEER, EDWARD (Folder 1)
  - 1. 1878, June 18,A. L. S. to G. W. Nichols
  - 2. 1878, July [5].A. L. S. to G. W. Nichols
  - 3. 1885, Oct 17.A. L. S.
  - 4. 1887, Feb. 19.A. L. S.
- ASHENDENE PRESS (Folder 2)
- BOOK CLUB OF CALIFORNIA (Folder 3)
  - 1. Ptd. application for membership
  - 2. 1914, Dec. 15.to Frederick E. Brasch signed by [UNK], Pres; John G. Howell, Albert M. Bender & Frederick A. [UNK]., T.L.S.
  - 3. 1915, Jan. 6.Clip on Grolier Club
- BORDEN PRESS (Folder 4)
  - 1. 1954, Dec. 2.Ptd. Christmas card of John W. Borden
  - 2. 1955, Sept. 18.Ptd announcement of John W. Borden
- COBDEN-SANDERSON, THOMAS JAMES 1840-1922 (Bookbinder, Printer) (Folder 5)
  - 1. 1898.Frances Quelle Lane to A.M. Bender, Mar. 17, 1940, A.N.S. Autographed photo.
  - 2. 1911, June 20..to Mr. John D. Blake, A.L.S.
  - 3. 1917, Mar. 7.T.L. to Mr. [John Henry] Nash.
  - 4. 1920to Mrs. Millard, Mar. 1, 1920, A.L.S.
- DANIEL, CHARLES HENRY OLIVE (Folder 6)
  - 1. to Mr. Rose, A.L.S.
- ELLIOT, JIM (Folder 7)
  - 1. to A.B. Kennedy. 7-19-55, A.L.S.
- GESSLER, CLIFFORD (Publisher?) (Folder 8)
  - 1944, Sept. 20.to Mrs. Sloss, T.L.S.
- GOUDY, FREDERIC W. (Folder 9)
  - 1. 1913, Sept. 2.Telegram to Taylor, Nash & Taylor
  - 2. 1913, Dec. 29to Gentlemen [Taylor, Nash & Taylor?], A.L.S.
  - 3. 1914, Jan. 24.to Gentlemen, A.L.S.
  - 4. 1914, July 31.to Gentlemen, A.L.S.
  - 5. 1914, Aug. 10.to Taylor, Nash & Taylor from Bertha M. Goudy, A.L.S.
  - 6. 1914, Nov. 5,to Taylor, Nash & Taylor, T.L.S.
  - 7. 1915, Sept. 13,to Mr. Taylor, A.L.S.
  - 8. 1916, Oct 21,to the Taylors, T.L.S.
  - 9. 1916, Aug 26,to Mr. Taylor, A.L.S.
  - 10. 1916, Nov. 22,to Mr. Taylor, A.L.S.
- HARPER, HENRY HOWARD (Folder 10)
  - 1. 1920, Nov. 1,to Morgan A. Gunst, T.L.S.
  - 2. [1912]to Morgan A. Gunst, T.L.S.
- HOLLINGS, FRANK (Book Dealer) (Folder 11)
  - 1. 1937, Dec. 22,T.L. to James Sandoe. Signature is a stamp.
  - 2. 1937, Nov. 30.Bill
- 3/13/33 C.H., A.L.S. (Folder 11a)
  - St. John Hornby to Sir Sydney Cockerell
- 4/22/71, A.L.S.
  - Cecily Hornby to J. Barclay
- KENNERLEY, MITCHELL (Folder 12)
  - 1940, Jan. 13,to Mr. Gunst, A.L.S.
- KIMBALL, DORR EDWIN (1882 - 1925) (Folder 13)
  - 1. 1920, Aug. 16Example of printing with to Alfred, A.N.S.
  - 2. 1920, Sept. 3to A.B. Kennedy, T.L.S.
  - 3. 1921, July 30.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 4. 1921, July [31].A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 5. 1921, Aug. 1.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 6. 1921, Aug. 2.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 7. 1921, Aug. 3.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 8. 1921, Aug. 4.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 9. 1921, Aug. 5.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 10. 1921, Aug. 6.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 11. 1921, Aug. 8.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 12. 1921, Aug. 9.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 13. 1921, Aug. 13.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 14. 1921, Aug. 15.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 15. 1921, Aug. 30.A. Pc S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 16. 1921, Sept. 10.to A.B. Kennedy from Helen M. Kimball, T.L.S.
  - 17. 1921, Sept. 21.A. Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 18. 1921, Sept. 26.to A. B. Kennedy from Helen M. Kimball, T.L.S.
  - 19. 1921, Oct. 8.T.L. to A. B. Kennedy from?
  - 20. 1921, Oct. 13.A. Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 21. 1921, Oct. 26.A. Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 22. 1921, Nov. 4.A. Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 23. 1921, Dec. 13.A. Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 24. 1922, Jan. 3.A. Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 25. 1922, Jan 13.A. Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 26. 1922, Jan. 20.A. Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 27. 1922, Jan. 27.A. Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy.
  - 28. 1922, Mar. 6.to A.B. Kennedy, T.L.S.
  - 29. 1922, Mar. 14.to A.B. Kennedy from Helen M. Kimball, T.L.S.
  - 30. 1922, Mar. 31.to A.B. Kennedy, T.L.S.
  - 31. 1922, May 10.to A.B. Kennedy, T.L.S.
  - 32. 1922, May 23.A.Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy
  - 33. 1922, July 8.A.Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy
  - 34. 1922, Aug. 3.A.Pc. S. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy
  - 35. 1922, Aug. 12.to Alfred Brooks Kennedy, A.L.S.
  - 36. 1924, Mar. 25.to Alfred Brooks Kennedy, T.L.S.
  - 37. 1924, Apr. 14.T.L. to Alfred Brooks Kennedy
  - 38. [1924] July 14.to A.B. Kennedy from Helen M. Kimball, T.L.S.
  - 39. 1925, Jan. 24.to Rauel L. Kennedy, T.L.S.
  - 40. 1925, Mar. 28.to R.L. Kennedy from Helen M. Kimball, T.L.S.
  - 41. n.d.Clip. Obit. notice of D.E. Kimball
  - 42. 1925, Apr. 16.to R.L. Kennedy from Helen M. Kimball, T.L.S.
  - 43. n.d.Frag. to unknown, A.L.S.
  - 44. n.d.Clip on death & work of Kimball by Helen M. Kimball
- KINSMAN, JOHN (Folder 14)
  - 1. 1874, Mar. 18. &cvr. to John S. Phene, A.L.S.
- LAKESIDE PRESS (Folder 15)
  - 1956, Feb.Printed announcement
- MASTERS, JAMES E. (Folder 16)
  - 1928, Mar. 22.to Nathan Van Patten, A.L.S.
- NASH, JOHN HENRY (Folder 17)
  - 1937, Jan. 7.to Mrs. Marvin R. Higgins, T.L.S.
- ORIOLI, GUISEPPE 1884 - 1942 (Folder 18)
  - 1. 1931, May 13.to [Richard Aldington], s. Pino., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1932, Aug. 6.to [Richard Aldington], s. Pino., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1934, Mar. 7.to [Richard Aldington], s. Pino., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1936, Dec 26.A.Pc.S. to [Richard Aldington], s. Pino.
  - 5. n.d., Mar. 17.to [Richard Aldington], s. Pino., A.L.S.
- ROGERS, BRUCE 1870 - (Folder 19)
  - 1. 1945, Nov. 19.to Mr. Taylor, A.L.S.
  - 2. 1945, Nov. 27.to Rogers from Edward DeWitt Taylor, T.L.S.
  - 3. 1945, Dec. 9.to Mr. Taylor & cvr., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1949, Jan 6. O Literary Swizzle-stick., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1949, Jan 6.Typed transcript & carbon of above
  - 6. 1955, May 31.Clip from Library of Congress Information Bulletin
  - 7. n.d.Misc. notes re: Rogers' work
- ROXEBURGHE, JAMES INNES KER, 5th Duke of 1738 - 1823 (Folder 20)
  - 1812, Oct. 7.Photostat of to Lord Napier, A.L.S.
- RUSSELL, THOMAS, C. (Folder 21a)
  - 1930, June 9.and cvr. to Helen B. Sutliff, A.L.S.
- SWALLOW, ALAN (Folder 21b)
  - 1963 Mar 15, 22 pg typescript by Phillips about the publisher, Alan Swallow, written for a Library school seminar. The typescript was notated by Alan Swallow on May 2 1963. Included is the letter from Phillips to Swallow asking for comments, as well as Swallow's return letter. The paper was partially based on a 5 page questionnaire which is included in appendix 2. Also included are book lists of Swallow's titles.
    J. Richard Phillips gift (1979)
- WARDE, BEATRICE (Folder 22)
  - 1963, Dec. 31.to Bill & Dorothy. Profumo disaster, death of Pope John, Kennedy assassination - short comments, Xerox copy of A.L.S.
- ZEITLIN, JAKE (Folder 23)
  - 1954, Mar. 18.to [William B.] Ready and typescript re: Lord Dunsany, A.L.S.